大家好
Hey, everyone.
最近怎么样
What‘s up?
我是Rob Dodson
It’s Rob Dodson.
欢迎回到Polycast
Welcome back to Polycast.
最近  有些爱好者给我留言
Recently, a few of you have left some comments
问我能不能专门针对neon-animation元素做一期讲座
asking if I could do an episode on the neon-animation elements.
鉴于我们已经做过与行为相关的内容了
Now, since we did an episode previously on behaviors,
我觉得是时候
I thought now
该深入讲讲和动画相关的东西了
would be a great time to dive into the animation stuff.
那么接下来我们进入tablet town  开始时间操作吧
So come on down to tablet town, and let‘s get hacking.
那么neon-animations   它到底是个什么东西呢
So neon-animations, what exactly are these things?
neon-animation是很多行为和元素的集合
Well, neon-animations are a collection
通过它们  开发者可以调用Web Animation(网页动画)
of behaviors and elements that let you use Web Animations.
如果大家没听说过Web Animation
And if you’ve never heard of Web Animations before,
简而言之  它是一套新的标准
it‘s basically a new set of standards
它将CSS和JavaScript动画统一了起来
that unify CSS and JavaScript animations.
所以你可以用JavaScript实现你的动画
So you can write your animation in JavaScript
实现一些很程序化的并且很棒的效果
and do something that’s really programmatic and awesome,
不同的是它会运行在GPU上  就好像CSS动画一样
but have it run on the GPU like it was a CSS animation.
它可以将那些看上去古板的登陆页面什么的
So this lets you turn your kind of boring sign-in form
转换成这样厉害的漂亮的效果
or whatever into this crazy, awesome, bouncy thing.
可能吹的有点过了  不过无所谓了
And I realize that‘s sort of over the top, but whatever.
你懂的
You get the point.
那么今天在这里我们接下来的内容是
So today what we’re going to do is
重点聊聊neon-animation中的行为接口
we‘re going to focus on the behaviors in the neon-animations set.
之后在另外一个视频里
And then in another episode, I’m going to do a followup
我会紧接着介绍元素集  比如neon-animated页面
and cover the elements, like neon-animated pages.
如果大家还不清楚‘行为’是什么
If you‘re not sure what behaviors are,
那么大家可以看看这里的视频
you check out this video right here
稍微脑补一下‘行为’的概念以及它的工作机制
and get caught up on behaviors so you can learn how they work.
了解了大概的概念之后
And then once you’ve seen that, come back
再回来看现在的视频即可
and check out this video.
今天我们要研究的行为包括
So the behaviors we‘re going to work on today are
neon-animation-behavior
the neon-animation-behavior
和neon-animation-runner-behavior
and the neon-animation-runner-behavior.
首先是neon-animatable-behavior
So the neon-animatable-behavior--
它的功能是能够在元素中添加动画
what this does is it allows you to add animations to your elements.
比如你可以添加淡出效果的动画
So you can add like a fade-in animation
或者放大效果的动画  很多很多酷炫的东西
or a scale-up animation, lots of really cool stuff there.
但是它所欠缺的是它无法让你
But what this doesn’t do is it doesn‘t allow you to actually
播放这些动画
play those animations.
也就是说它里面没有实现回放功能
There’s no playback built into this thing.
而对于回放功能
So for playback support, that‘s when you need
你就需要用到neon-animation-runner-behavior
the neon-animation-runner-behavior.
通过它来实现回放功能
So that gives us playback.
而且更加厉害的是
Now, what’s really cool about the
neon-animation-runner-behavior也实现了
neon-animation-runner-behavior is it actually implements this
animatable-behavior
animatable-behavior as well.
所以对于今天要实现的元素
So for the elements that we‘re going to be building today,
我们唯一要搞定的行为就是
the only behavior that we need to work with
这个neon-animation-runner  它真的很棒
is neon-animation-runner, which is awesome.
现在  你也许有点困惑  为什么会存在这个行为呢？
Now, you might wonder, why this does behavior exist even?
在接下来的视频中
Well, neon-animatable is going to become
从我们看到动态的页面后就会发现
more important when we go and we look at the animated pages
neon-animatable将会变得更加重要
elements in that following episode.
不过今天在这里我们仅仅用到neon-animation-runner
But today, we’re just going to work on neon-animation-runner.
所以我们即将要实现的就是
So the thing that we‘re going to build
这个可弹出的注册表单
is this little sort of pop-up sign-up form thing.
当我们点击'Open'按钮的时候  它会播放动画
So you can see here I click this Open button, it animates in.
点击'Close'按钮  它会淡出
I click the Close button, it fades out.
我看到这里已经有一个&lt;paper-dialog&gt;元素了
Now, I realize there’s already a paper dialog element.
所以如果你正在实现一个登录表单
And if you‘re building a sign-in form, you should absolutely,
那么你毫无疑问应该使用&lt;paper-dialog&gt;元素
100% use the paper dialog element.
这里我自己创建了一个  仅作为教学使用
I created my own one just as a teaching aid
通过它可以帮助我们
because it’s going to help us really
更加直观地了解neon-animation集合中的概念
illustrate a lot of the concepts in the neon-animation set.
所以如果大家需要构造一个登录表单
By all means, if you‘re actually building a sign-in form,
那么一定记住要用paper dialog
go use paper dialog.
对于我自定义的元素  这儿有个bower.json
So for my element, here’s the bower.json for it.
我的元素叫login-panel
My element is called login-panel.
这里有趣的地方就是
And the interesting thing here is just
只要向下一滚动  它就会自动检查依赖
to scroll down and check out its dependencies.
大家能够看到这里我会引入paper-elements 1.0
And you can see I‘m importing paper-elements 1.0
和neon-elements 1.0
and neon-elements 1.0.
其实有时候我也特别懒
And I’m often pretty lazy.
我会把整个paper和neon-element元素集都引入进来
I‘ll import like the entire paper- and neon-element sets
因为从我的角度出发
when I’m developing because from my perspective,
将所有的这些元素集都引用进来
it doesn‘t really matter if you pull all these sets
没有什么不妥的
into your development environment.
实际上在软件发布版本中的文件大小
Your file size, what you actually ship into production,
是由你引用的内容和你所实现的内容而定的
is only what you import and only what you vulcanize.
所以我其实特别懒
So I’m often lazy.
我会把整个集合都引用进来
I‘ll pull in the full sets just so I can
这样开发起来也比较方便
have an easier time developing.
在我的编辑器中
Now, inside of my editor, this is the definition
这是login-panel元素的定义
for my login-panel element.
你可以看到这里有些风格化的设计
You can see that we’ve got some styles here.
需要解释的是在主元素中
The one to note is that on the host element,
我们将显示默认设置为了空
we‘ve set display none by default,
所以在一开始你什么都看不到
so you just can’t see the thing initially.
当上下滚动时，就能看到模板的痕迹
And then scrolling around, you can see the templates.
这是比较标准的Polymer
Pretty vanilla Polymer.
我们已经有了paper-material元素
We‘ve got paper-material element, which
它会帮助我们实现小卡片的效果
is going to give us a little card,
还有paper-inputs用来实现登录表单
and we’ve got some paper-inputs for the sign-in form.
再往下  你会在JavaScript中看到实际的元素定义
And further down, you‘ve got the actual definition
都是很典型的东西
for the element down here in JavaScript, so pretty typical stuff.
我将它称为login-panel
I’ve called it login-panel.
它现在有一个属性  是布尔型的
It‘s got one property right now, this opened Boolean,
这里还有两个方法  显示和隐藏
and then I’ve got these two methods, show and hide.
它们的作用就是改变显示风格
What these are going to do is just change the display style
通过显示与隐藏将风格从内嵌模块到消失进行转换
from inline-block to none depending on if it‘s showing or hiding.
所以现在如果你调用这些方法
So right now if you just call these methods,
这些元素会在屏幕上闪一下
the element’s just going to, like, blink on screen
然后很快就消失了
and then disappear really, really quickly.
但是我们本来是想实现动画效果的  对吧？
But I want this thing to animate, right?
我希望能为其中添加一些活力
I want it to add a little pizzazz.
要实现这些  先回到最顶层的元素
So to do that, I‘ll go back up to the top of the element
添加一些动画
and I’m going to add imports for some animations.
而且最酷的地方是neon-animations
Now, the cool thing is the neon-animations set
内置了一些预置动画  你可以任意使用
actually comes with a few prefab animations that you can just drop in.
现在我要添加一个放大动画
So I‘m going to pull in a scale-up animation,
一个淡出动画
a fade-out animation, and then I’m
然后我还会把animation-runner-behavior添加进来
also going to pull in that animation-runner-behavior.
现在我希望大家
So check out these file paths right here just
来看一下这里的文件路径
because I want you see this.
所有的东西都是源自于neon-animation
So everything‘s coming from the neon-animation package,
通过该源码包我能够获得动画路径
and then I’ve got this animations directory.
这里包含我之前提到的预置动画
This is where the prefab animations hang out.
而且在neon-animation包中
And then also in neon-animation package,
只要引用那个行为
I‘m just pulling in that behavior.
那么这里就全搞定了
So we’re all set up there.
现在我可以滚动到下面  将这个行为
Now I‘m ready to scroll down and I can add the behavior
添加到我的元素定义中去了
to my elements definitions.
在我的行为队列中
So in my behaviors array,
我会添加neon-animation-runner-behavior
I’ll add neon-animation-runner-behavior.
这样做的效果就是
And what that‘s going to do is it’s
提供animationConfig属性
going to give me access to this animationConfig property.
所以记住  行为组件的工作原理是
So remember, the way that behaviors work
它将属性和方法融入到了你的元素中
is they mix in properties and methods into your elements.
所以通过添加行为
So by adding that behavior, I now
我现在就可以使用animationConfig属性了
have access to this really cool animationConfig thing.
而这里就是我能够在我自己的元素中添加动画的地方
And this is where I can set up all of the animations on my element.
要实现这个目的  这里会返回一个对象
So to do this, I‘m going to return an object,
这个对象中的每个键值
and every key inside of this object
就是我们要添加的动画的名称
is going to be the name of an animation that I want to run.
这里我要创建一个叫做entry的组件
So I’m going to create one called entry.
而这个对象的值  这个名称
And the values for this entry object, the name,
就是它将要播放的动画的名称
is going to be the name of the animation it should execute,
也就是我们之前引用的放大的动画
which is that scale-up animation that we imported.
而这个节点(node)  它就是动画的目标
And then the node, this is the target of the animation.
在这里  我们的目的是
So in this case, we‘re saying, I want
让这个元素自己活动起来
this element to animate itself.
所以我们要传递这个
So I’m just passing this.
但是如果这里
But if there were children inside of here
还有你想要播放动画的子元素你可以使用其它一些组件
that you wanted to animate, you could use something
比如Polymer的节点自动搜索功能
like Polymer‘s automatic node finding.
你可以这样写  this.$.child
You could be like, I want this .$.
将一些子元素作为目标
some child to be the target.
我想要让那个元素活动起来
I want that thing to animate instead.
但是在这  我们的设计是
But in this case, we’re just saying, hey, animate myself
用这个进入动画让它动起来
with this entry animation.
而且可以同时构造一个退出动画
And then we can also create an exit animation.
在这里会调用淡化动画作为退出动作
So this time I‘m going to call fade-out for that exit animation.
然后在下面这里  在显示和隐藏方法里
And then I’m going to go down here into the show
添加两个播放动画的调用
and hide methods and add two calls to play animation.
所以记住  我之前提到过的animatable-behavior
So remember, I said the animatable-behavior, that‘s
它是我们能够向元素添加动画的关键要素
what lets us actually add animations to an element.
然后就是animation-runner-behavior
And then the animation-runner-behavior,
它会为我们提供动画回放的功能
that‘s what gives us playback support.
它们就是这些调用方法的来源
So that’s where these methods come from.
我们这里仅仅调用刚才
And again, we‘re just calling the named animations
我们所创建的动画
that we just created up there.
如果大家的眼睛够敏捷
One thing that you might notice if you’re astute
那么这里大家也许会注意到一件事
and you‘re sort of paying attention
在隐藏方法中
here is that right here inside of hide, we’re
在执行动画前  我们会将显示设置为空
setting display to none before we execute the animation.
也就是说它会让屏幕闪烁一下
So that means that this thing would just blink off screen
然后我们就看不到它了
and we would never see it.
这样我们就能从屏幕上去掉它
So we can take this out.
我们可以在这里去掉这一行代码
We can actually remove that line there.
我会稍微注释一下
I‘ll remove it with a little comment.
不过我们一会还会返回来看这段代码
But we’re going to need to revisit this in just a bit,
到时候我会向大家解释原因
and I‘ll show you why.
但是首先  我们先来预览一下我们的元素
But first, let’s preview our element.
所以在这里  当我点击‘Open’按钮时
So over here when I click this Open button,
它会调用显示方法
it‘s going to call that show method.
当我点击’Close’按钮
When I click this Close button, it’s
它会调用隐藏方法
going to call the hide method.
我点击Open时  会出现放大的动画
So I click Open, animates in with scale-up.
当我点击‘Close’按钮的时候  看看会发生什么
Then I click Close, and watch what‘s going to happen.
它会淡出  然后页面会恢复到之前
It fades out, but then it sort of pops back to the state
的样子
it was in before.
那么这里发生了什么呢
So what’s going on there?
Web Animations不会保留
Well, Web Animations don‘t actually
你在自己元素上所做的状态修改
preserve changes that you make to the state of your elements.
所以如果你修改了CSS属性或者类似的东西
So if you’re changing the CSS properties or something
记住不会有改变会被保留
like that, there‘s no preservation.
最初我想  这也太烂了
At first I was like, well, that sort of sucks.
而我还是希望能保留一些状态的改变
I kind of wish it did preserve those changes.
不过后来我就发现这样做很难调试
But then I realized that would be potentially very difficult to debug.
如果你创建了一个复杂的动画
If you had a complex animation that
里面在一个元素中用到了很多风格化设置和属性
was applying lots of styles and properties to an element,
这就很难搞清楚一些事
it‘d be very hard later to figure out, like,
比如会改变尺寸之类的
when did that thing change its size or whatever.
Web Animations提到  这些都由你决定
So Web Animation says, hey, that’s going to be up to you.
你需要保留所有状态上的变化
You‘re going to need to preserve whatever state changes you do.
你可以通过添加一个类
And you can do that by adding a class
或者修改风格属性来实现这个功能  就像我们这里做的一样
or just manipulating the style property like we were doing.
那么我们如何实现它呢
So how do we do that?
回到元素定义中
Well, back in our elements definition,
我将要在这里添加一个listeners对象(listeners)
I’m going to add a listeners object.
如果大家从来没用过listeners对象
And if you‘ve never worked with the listeners object before,
它非常有用
it’s really useful.
现在  这个是所有Polymer元素都具备的
Now, this is something that all Polymer elements get.
listeners对象基本上
And the listeners object
是AddEventListener的简化表示
is basically shorthand for AddEventListener.
所以我们会说
So we‘re going to say, hey, I want
我想为NeonAnimationFinish事件创建一个监听对象
to create a listener for the NeonAnimationFinish event.
我们称它为onNeonAnimationFinish方法
And I want it to call this onNeonAnimationFinish method,
会在下面的代码中实现它
which I’m going to define down here below.
所以当动画播放完成后  会调用这个方法
So when the element is done animating, call this method.
在这个方法中
And inside of this method, we‘re going
我们会先检查它是否被打开
to check to see if it’s opened or not.
如果它没被打开  我们就会让它显示为空
And if it‘s not open, we’ll tell it to display none.
那么我们返回去  看一下我们的动画
So now we can go back and we can check our animation out.
点击’Open’按钮  它的效果和之前一样
So click the Open button, and it animates as it was before.
现在当我点击‘Close’按钮的时候  状态会被保留
And now when I click Close, that state gets preserved.
厉害吧
Awesome.
那么如果你想添加多重动画到你的元素
So what if you want to add multiple animations
比如所有的动画都在同一时间播放怎么办呢
to your element that all kind of play at the same time?
其实很简单
Well, that‘s actually really easy to do,
我会在这给大家展示如何实现
and I can show you how to do it over here.
不过首先  先引用一些动画
But first, let’s import a few more animations to work with.
我先添加一个淡入动画
So I‘m going to pull in a fade-in animation,
然后再添加一个滑入动画
and I’m also going to pull in one called slide-down.
在我的animationConfig对象中
And down in my animationConfig object, instead
我会添加一个数组
of just having a single entry object here,
来替换之前的那个单独的entry对象
I can actually have an array.
这样我就能够添加一组想要播放的动画了
So I can have an array of animation objects that I would like to play.
大家可以看到这里我已经添加了一个
You can see here that I‘ve set the first one, the animation
动画的名字叫slide-down-animation(滑入动画)
name, to slide-down-animation, and then
第二个是fade-in-animation(淡入动画)
the second one, fade-in-animation.
而这两个动画会平行播放
And these two animations are going to play in parallel.
也就是说它们会在同一时间进行播放
So they’re both going to be happening at the same time.
我们先来在Chrome里预览一下
So let‘s go preview that over in Chrome just
看看会发生什么
to see what that does.
来点击一下‘Open’按钮
So I’m going to click the Open button,
你会看到多个动画在同一时间
and you‘ll see it sort of slides down and animates
进行播放
at the same time.
它会淡入同时滑入
So it fades in and slides down both at the same time.
酷  但是如果你想稍微安排一下动画播放的时间怎么办呢
Cool, but what if you wanted to sort of change the timing of that?
也许你希望你的动画顺序播放
Maybe you want your animations to play sequentially
或者希望他们的播放顺序稍微有点间隔
or you want them to be offset slightly.
实现起来也很简单
Well, that’s really easy to do as well.
每个动画对象也带有一个可选的时间对象
So every animation object also has an optional timing
可供大家进行设置
object that you can give it.
时间对象含有一些大家可以使用的属性
And the timing object has a few properties that you can work with.
你可以设置动画播放时长
You could set duration.
我觉得这里slide-down-animation动画应该
So I‘m going to say that the slide-down-animation animation
播放2000毫秒  也就是2秒
should have a duration of 2,000 milliseconds, so two seconds.
而淡入动画会播放大约1000毫秒
And my fade-in animation should have
也就是1秒钟  并且延迟1000毫秒播放
a duration of 1,000, so one second, and a delay of 1,000.
所以它会在播放之前等待1秒钟
So it’s going to wait one second before it starts playing,
然后再播放1秒钟时间
and then it‘s going to only be a second long,
所以它会和slide-down-animation一起结束
so it’ll end at the same time as the slide-down-animation.
可以利用延迟的功能来
And you can use delay to have your animations play
顺序播放你的动画
kind of like one right after the other.
如果你望动画播放的时候稍微有些间隔
Or if you want things to be sort of offset,
有点像多重动画的效果  也可以实现
just kind of on top of one another, you can do that as well.
而它的作用就是
And what this is going to do is it‘s really
它会改变动画的感觉
going to change the feel of this animation.
看看这个的效果   拿它和之前我们所实现的效果进行比较
So watch this and kind of compare it to what we were doing before.
当我点击’Open’时  它会平缓的播放动画
Now when I click Open, it’s a much more
动画衔接的也更加平顺
gradual, kind of smoother transition
正如我们这里看到的一样
that we see there because it doesn‘t even
当滑动到一半的时候
start fading in until it’s about halfway
它才会开始淡入的动画
through the slide-down-animation.
所以仅仅是通过改变几个属性值
So just by changing those little properties,
就能够实现这样效果的动画
we were able to really alter the feel of that animation, which
真的很棒
is pretty cool.
现在  如何编写自己的动画呢？
Now, how would you go about writing your own animation?
听上去有点繁琐复杂令人生畏  是吧
Because it might seem really daunting,
但实际上实现起来很简单
but it‘s actually super easy.
我经常会看看
And what I usually do is I look at one of the animations that’s
预置动画集合中的动画
already in the prefab animation set,
然后将它作为起始点
and then I‘ll use that as a starting point.
这是淡入动画的定义
So this is the definition for the fade-in animation.
如果我们在这里滚动一下
And if we scroll around here, you
你会看到它很像其它的Polymer元素
can see that it looks a lot like any other Polymer element.
有些文档会详细说明它所支持的选项
There’s some documentation for the options that it supports.
我们来看看它的定义
And we go down and we look at its definition,
你会发现它包含一个‘is’属性
and you can see that it‘s just got an
代表它的名称
is property here for its name.
它实现了这个NeonAnimationBehavior
It implements this NeonAnimationBehavior.
我们还没聊过这个
We haven’t talked about that yet,
如果你要实现自己的动画
but that‘s the behavior you need to implement if you’re
那么你需要实现这个行为
creating your own animation.
它含有这个config函数
And then it has this config function.
这就是实现动画中内部的机制
And this is really the meat of the animation here,
并没有那么复杂
and it‘s really not that complex.
你会发现动画的目标节点
You can see that the node that it’s targeting
就是我们在configuration所传入的节点
is whatever node we passed in in our configuration.
它会创建一个叫做KeyframeEffect的组件
And then it creates what‘s called a KeyframeEffect.
就在这里  这是Web Animations API
And this right here, this is the Web Animations API at work.
所以我们要创建一个KeyframeEffect对象
So we’re creating a KeyframeEffect Object.
我们会告诉它以哪个节点作为对象
We‘re telling it which node to target,
然后我们会把这一组用JavaScript实现的关键帧数组
and then we pass it this array of key frames that
传递给它
are written out in JavaScript.
这里我们希望不透明度的值从0变到1
And here we’re just saying we want it to go from 0 to 1
同时我们还会设置时间参数
in terms of opacity, and we also pass in the timing stuff.
特别简单
So this is pretty easy.
你很快就发现如何快速
You could quickly see how you could just kind
模仿这样的实现方法  然后实现你自己的动画
of mimic this and implement your own animation,
就像我在这里做的一样
and that‘s exactly what I did.
我创建了一个回弹动画
I created a bounce-in animation.
这里我们要创建类似弹跳的效果
So we’re going to create kind of a bouncing effect.
我提取了之前我们用到的放大效果的动画
And I took that scale-up animation we were working with before.
把它的实现代码粘贴到这里
I just copied it and pasted it in here.
你会发现在其中有很多我们之前已经接触过的
You can see that it‘s got pretty similar options to the thing we
相类似的选项
were just working with.
唯一的区别就是这个transformOrigin
Really, the only difference is this transformOrigin
就是这个选项
configuration thing here, which just
它可以让我们设置动画放大的起始点
lets us set the origin point we’ll be scaling from.
其它的实现体就都和之前的一样了
But then everything else is the same.
我所做的就是将所有这些不同的关键帧
And what I did was I added all these different key frames
添加进来
along the way.
从放大级数0到最终放大级数1
So start at scale 0, work up to scale 1,
这里有一些关键帧类似间隙的效果
and then here are the key frames sort of interstitially
来保证图形不会变得太大或者太小
for getting too big and too small and too big and too small
直到整体的回弹效果显得比较自然为止
until you have what looks like kind of a cool bouncing effect.
实现体全部都在这了
So really, this is all there is to it.
而且如果你希望
And if you want,you can also,
我也相信大家有能力将其他一些效果混合进来
I believe, mix in other things here.
比如图形变换和不透明度还有其他一些效果
So you could have transform and opacity and a few other things
让他们在同一时间进行播放
running at the same time.
它的作用就是让我们能够
But what this gives us is the ability
好好理解animationConfig对象
to go over to our animationConfig object.
我们可以将入口动画替换为
We can replace our entry animation
回弹动画
with that bounce-in animation,
然后可以将这个定义引用进来
and then we can import its definition.
有了它在  一切都搞定了
And with that in place, we‘re all good.
我们可以直接保存  然后点击‘Open’按钮
We can just go and click the Open button.
现在大家可以看到这个
And now you’ll see we get this kind
有点疯狂的回弹效果
of frantic bounce-in effect, which is a little crazy.
我们返回来
So we go back.
为这个动画添加一些时间参数
We add some timing to this thing,
把播放时间稍微延长一点
we stretch out the duration a little bit.
然后播放它
And now when we play it,
这回看上去效果好多了
it‘s a much more digestible animation.
比刚才能更平滑一些
It’s a little bit smoother.
现在  我给大家展示的这些关键帧
Right now, these key frames that I showed you,
都会按照生命周期或者动画的播放时间
these are all being evenly distributed
进行平均分布
across the life cycle or the duration of that animation.
所以它们都花了相同的时长
So they all take the exact same amount
这并不是使用动画的合理方式
of time, which is not really how animation works.
通常情况下  你会希望某些部分的动画时间长些
Oftentimes, you want some parts to be longer
某些部分的动画时间短些
and some parts to be shorter.
如果要实现这样的效果  也十分简单
And so if you want to do that, it‘s also very easy.
你可以在关键帧的动画中增加偏移量
You can just add offsets to your key frame animations,
就像大家在这里看到的一样
and so you can see here that I’m offsetting from 0
把偏移量从0改为1
and we‘re going to go all the way up to 1.
你可以把这个看作是
So you can think about this at like 0% of your animation
动画时间从0%变为100%
duration to 100% of your animation duration.
这就是动画之间的
And this is the amount of time that should go on
时间间隔
between each of these.
那么图形从0变为80%大小的时候
So from 0 to basically 80% through the lifespan
我希望这段动画
of the animation, I want to spend
播放的时间为1.5秒
all that time just scaling up to 1.5, just
在这里修改最初的关键帧之间的转化
doing this initial sort of key frame tween here.
然后放大动画中剩下的20%
And then I want the other 20% of my animation
结合一点回弹的效果直到播放结束
to just be occurring with the bouncing bits at the very end.
所以放大动画会稍微长一些
So it’ll be a long scale-up and then
它会在最后很快的回弹一下
it‘ll bounce really, really fast all at the end there.
如果大家预览一下
So if we go and we preview this, you’ll
就能看到这个稍长的放大动画
see now that it‘s a longer scale-up
和结束前的回弹效果
and we get more of that bounce at the end.
非常棒
So pretty cool.
要达到让人满意的效果
Pretty easy way to really dial in the look
最简单的方法就是细细品味你自己的动画
and feel your animation
以达到满意的效果
so you get exactly what you want.
最后我想说一件事
The last thing I want to mention--
当我录制视频的时候  我在动画的调用接口中
as I was recording this, I came across a little bug
发现了一个小bug  我们看这里
in the animation system, so watch here.
我要点一下‘Open’按钮
I’m going to click the Open button.
然后播放我自己的动画
I‘m going to play my animation.
然后再点击’Close’按钮
And then I’m going to click this Close button
然后再点两次‘Close’按钮
and I‘m going to click the Close button twice.
而当我再次点击‘Open’按钮的时候  都看不到动画了
And now when I click Open again, I no longer see my animation.
这是为什么呢？
So what’s up there?
貌似有这么一个bug  当你的动画加载的时候
Well, there seems to be a bug where if your animations stack,
它会出现崩溃
it can break, which means it is time
看来是时候请出我们的老朋友The Sweet Hacks了
to bust out our old friend (DEEP VOICE) The Sweet Hacks.
有段时间没用到它了
It‘s been a little while since we saw them,
不过现在我们需要它
but now they’re back.
当我在handler实现的时候
What I‘m going to do is in my handlers,
需要调用CancelAnimation方法
I’m going to add a call to this CancelAnimation method.
调用CancelAnimation方法时
So when I call CancelAnimation, it just
它会抛出其它动画正在播放的异常
throws out what other animation was already playing.
当我点击‘Open’的时候  它反弹了
And now when I click Open, it bounces.
双击‘Close’的时候  它会关闭
I double-click Close, it closes.
再点击‘Open’  它又变了
I click Open, and it works again.
说明我们的方法对了
We‘re back on track.
所以我发现这个bug让人头疼
So I realize it’s kind of an annoying bug,
不过我希望把那个包含进来
but I wanted to include that little pro tip for you
以方便后面用到的朋友有所参考
in case anyone else runs into that issue.
好吧
All right.
那么我们今天谈了一大堆东西
Wow, we covered a ton of stuff today.
我需要承认  当开始这些内容的时候
And I‘ve got to admit, when I started this,
我实际上对动画开发接口不是特别熟悉
I didn’t actually know a lot about the animation system.
所以学习的时候感觉特别酷
So it‘s been really cool for me to learn,
希望大家也能够乐在其中
and I hope you all enjoyed it as well.
接下来我们会做
Now, I’m going to do
一个后续的特辑来讲解一下动态页面
a followup episode on the animated pages
元素
element.
点一下‘Subcribe’按钮就能获得所有内容
So click that little Subscribe button so you don‘t miss that.
感谢大家观看
As always, thank you so much for watching,
我们下次再见
and I’ll see you next time.
大家好  我是Rob
Hey, there, Polycasters, Rob here.
现在是提问时间
QA time.
Alex Shaw写道
Alex Shaw writes in and asks, What
如果一个开发者从Polymer 0.5转到Polymer 1.0
is one quick tip you‘d give someone
你会给他哪些忠告呢
who’s moving from Polymer 0.5 to Polymer 1.0?
问得好  Alex
So good question, Alex.
最近  Polymer团队的一个成员
Recently, one of the members of the Polymer team
实现了一个非常棒的模块  叫polyup
wrote this really, really cool module called polyup.
实际上它会替换你的Polymer 0.5代码
And it will actually take your old Polymer 0.5 code
然后通过一些很牛的机制转换为Polymer 1.0代码
and do crazy machinations to it and spit out Polymer 1.0 code.
确实很棒
It is really awesome.
大家可以通过这个链接
So you can follow this link right here
了解更多关于polyup的信息
to check out the polyup website.
要把代码放进去  大家需要做一些小改动
There‘s a little repl where you can drop your code in
这样它就能自动转化了
and it’ll just automatically convert it.
而且大家还可以安装MPM模块
And there‘s also an MPM module that you
从命令行运行该模块
can install and just sort of run it from your command line, so
非常棒的东西
really cool stuff there.
谢谢你  Alex  谢谢你提出了这么好的问题
Again, thank you, Alex, for sending in a question.
我们会和大家简单打个招呼  给大家发一封反馈邮件
We’ll have our minions reach out to you and send you a swag pack.
如果大家有什么问题  记得在评论中留言就行
If you have questions, be sure to leave them down
没准会在以后的Polycast视频里
in the comments, and we just might feature you
提到大家的名字
on a future episode of Polycast.
感谢大家观看
So thank you all so much for watching,
我们下次再见
and I‘ll see you next time.